General.
My home is heavily guarded.
You dare make a move on me here?
When I came in,
the police had already surrounded the place.
They're all caught! Wrap it up!
They were taken down long ago.
Speak!
Why did you target the Lian family?
Because of your father, Lian Shanquan.
He refused to submit to me,
so I had to conquer him,
conquer the Lian family,
just as Japan is fated to conquer China!
In your dreams!
The Lian family won't lose to you,
Nor will the Chinese lose to Japan!
Speak! Where is Lian Yu?
Just moments ago,
I had Kobayashi Sachiko
send your brother out the secret passage.
Where did you send Lian Yu?
To a madman.
Where they'll forever be slaves to Japan.
I'll ask you one more time.
Where is my brother, Lian Yu?
Men made slaves,
women made whores.
Talk! Where's Lian Yu?
Brother Lian!
All of Matsui's men have been taken down.
Impossible. Impossible!
This kid...
I just saw him.
Really.
He seemed to head to Rongcheng Station.
The license plate is Guo 88909 Rong.
Guo 88909 Rong.
Let's go.
Lian Yu!
Brother!
Yuna!
Lian Yu!
Major General.
The night raid failed.
Our forces were completely wiped out.
Damn it!
Matsui, that useless fool!
Good for nothing...
and ruins everything!
Who is he?
A young slave Mr. Matsui kept captive.
What's your name?
Yuna.
Mr. Matsui named him Matsui Yuna.
He can't speak.
Yuna.
Kill!
So cute!
Besides the gold bars,
compressed rations,
first-aid kits, and essentials—
pack them all in.
Yes, Master.
What is going on?
War is coming.
We're running for our lives, of course!
I bought tickets to Hong Kong, China.
We're leaving today.
This money will last you a lifetime.
Go find somewhere to hide.
Thank you, Master.
Come on!
Let me take it.
Hello. Boat tickets, please.
Here you go.
All right.
Dad, the suitcase.
Let me grab the tickets.
Okay.
Go on, go on. Hurry up!
Mingyuan, hurry and get on!
Dad, I'm deputy chief of Rongcheng Police.
Protecting the people is my duty.
I can't leave.
Wait for me in Hong Kong, China.
Take care of yourself.
Son!
Mingyuan!
Forget that damn chief job!
Leave with me!
Leave with me, Mingyuan!
Time's up. We have to set sail.
Don't go! My son isn't on board yet!
You can't leave!
Mingyuan! Mingyuan!
You can't leave me behind, Mingyuan!
My son! My son!
Mingyuan!
April 19, 1941.
Under the cover of naval gunfire,
at Changle and Lianjiang,
the Japanese made multi-pronged landings.
The Japanese seized fishing boats
from islands along the Min River estuary.
Fishermen clashed with the Japanese,
suffering heavy casualties.
Warships in the Min River estuary
patrolled along the northern coast.
All-out war is imminent.
I called everyone here today
to make an announcement.
Lian Ye.
Come over here.
Everyone, Japan attacked Rongcheng today.
This dance hall can't protect any of you.
Thank you all for the past three years,
and everything you've given to this hall.
Without you,
there would be no Chen Dieyi today.
Here is severance pay for everyone.
Take it and run for your lives.
Reporting, Commander!
The Japanese breached the Min River line,
and landed on Jiadeng and Langqi islands.
Reporting, Commander!
The Japanese took Changle and Lianjiang,
and are pushing toward downtown Rongcheng!
I'm old, and my mind isn't as sharp.
I can't lead the Sanshan Gang brothers
to break through and survive.
You found Chief Hu's real killer.
Your capability is clear to all.
From this day forth,
you are the Chief of the Sanshan Gang.
Thank you, Sister Dieyi.
When the war ends
and the dance hall reopens,
you are all welcome to come back.
Thank you, Sister Dieyi.
Reporting, General!
A telegram from headquarters.
Downtown Rongcheng is unfit for battle,
ordering us to withdraw to Dahu, Minhou,
and hold the Gutian mountains.
Move out! Any later and it'll be too late!
General,
how can the police help the war effort?
Yan Baichuan pays respects to Chief Lian.
Greetings, Chief Lian!
My thanks to you all.
I, Lian Ye, hereby swear,
to give my all for the Sanshan Gang,
until my dying breath!
This is for you.
Sister Dieyi, I don't want to leave.
I want to stay with you forever.
Bailing,
you're still young.
It's dangerous to stay with me.
Hide far away.
Never let anyone find you.
Remember what I said.
Our top priority right now
is to keep the Sanshan Gang and fishermen
from clashing directly with the Japanese.
Pass down the order.
First,
the Japanese are seizing our fishing boats
to cut off the islands' connection
with Rongcheng.
Tell the fishermen to hide their boats
for emergencies.
Mingyuan,
you heard it just now.
At their current marching pace,
they will cross the Wulong River tomorrow
and march straight into Rongcheng.
Why don't you join us
and fall back to Dahu, Minhou?
Second, the garrison defends Rongcheng.
The civilians are unarmed;
they can't fight the Japanese directly.
Thank you, Commander.
I'm a native of Rongcheng.
Defending Rongcheng is my duty.
Finally,
the Japanese
will surely cut off our food and supplies.
Stockpile grain and prepare for battle!